(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-14T21:58:03.709945",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
天音かなた 卒業LIVE 『絶対的アイドル』
[Amane Kanata Graduation Live: The Absolute Idol]
絶対的少女S 天音かなた 卒業LIVE
[Absolute Girl S - Amane Kanata Graduation LIVE]
出会えた 奇跡に
Meeting you was a miracle
もう息が止まりそうだったよ
that almost took my breath away.
荒野のヒース
[Song: Heath of the Wilderness]
何をみているの
What are you looking at
どこまでも澄んだ瞳で
with your endlessly clear eyes?
ふたりだけを照らせる
Illuminating only the two of us,
世界でひとつ すべてがいま 始まるから
the one and only world... because everything is starting now.
君に逢うために生まれたと 伝えたいよ
I want to tell you that I was born to meet you.
荒野の風をも巻き起こす 視線をもつよ
Holding a gaze that could whip up even a desert wind,
ヒリヒリする声になるのさ ずっと 側にいる
my voice turns sharp and stinging... I will always stay by your side.
濁りのない 潔い気持ちは
This pure, unblemished feeling
ヒリヒリするほど 泣いてない
isn't crying to the point of pain;
ふたりきり 未来さえ超えるんだ
just the two of us will transcend even the future.
どこへ行くの 泣きそうな
Where are you going? Tears well up inside me,
自分に涙 あふれるけど
feeling like I'm about to cry, but...
走り出せる
I can still start running.
もういま はぐれたら
If we get separated right now,
身体ごと 消してみせる
I will make my whole body disappear.
花びらだった 一枚の 姿になって
Becoming the shape of a single fallen petal,
君の愛を求めて 旅するよ
I will journey in search of your love.
ずっと 君を抱きしめる
I will hold you close forever.
汚されない 潔い気持ちが
An unspotted, pure feeling
時を超えて 呼び合う
calls out across time.
ふたりきり 未来へと 届けたい
Just the two of us, I want to reach into the future.
出会えた 奇跡に
Meeting you was a miracle
もう息が止まりそうだったよ
that almost took my breath away.
繋いだ その手に
Holding onto that hand we joined,
少し強くなれる気がする
I feel like I can become a little stronger.
出会えた 奇跡に
Meeting you was a miracle
もう息が止まりそうだったよ
that almost took my breath away.
明日も 未来も
Tomorrow, and in the future,
ただどうしようもなく 好きだよ
I just helplessly love you.
いつか僕らの上をスレスレに
I strangely remember that airplane
通りすぎていったあの飛行機を
that flew so close right above us,
不思議なくらいに覚えてる
even though there was no real meaning to it,
意味もないのに なぜか
for some reason.
不甲斐なくて泣いた日の夜に
On the night of the day I cried from feeling pathetic,
ただ強くなりたいと願ってた
I just wished to become stronger.
そのために必要な勇気を
I was searching for the courage
探し求めていた
needed for that purpose.
残酷な運命が定まってるとして
Even if a cruel fate has already been decided,
それがいつの日か僕の前に現れるとして
and even if it appears before me someday,
ただ一瞬 この一瞬 息ができるなら
if I can breathe for just a moment, this single moment,
どうでもいいと思えた その心を
I felt that heart could think nothing else mattered...
もう一度 遠くへ行け遠くへ行けと
"Go further, go further once more,"
僕の中で誰かが歌う
someone sings inside of me,
どうしようもないほど熱烈に
so intensely that I can't help it.
いつだって目を腫らした君が二度と
So that you, who always had swollen eyes from crying,
悲しまないように笑える
can smile and never feel sad again—
そんなヒーローになるための歌
this is a song to become that kind of hero.
さらば掲げろピースサイン
Farewell, raise your peace sign
転がっていくストーリーを
to the story that keeps rolling on.
守りたいだなんて言えるほど
Enough to say I want to protect you,
君が弱くはないの分かってた
I knew you weren't weak.
それ以上に僕は弱くてさ
Even more than that, I was weak,
君が大事だったんだ
and you were precious to me.
「一人で生きていくんだ」なんてさ
Ever since the day I blurted out,
口をついて叫んだあの日から
"I'll live on my own!" and shouted,
変わっていく僕を笑えばいい
you can laugh at me as I change,
独りが怖い僕を
at me who is scared of being alone.
蹴飛ばして 噛み付いて 息もできなくて
Kicking, biting, unable to breathe,
騒ぐ頭と腹の奥がぐしゃぐしゃになったって
even if my noisy head and inner gut get all messed up,
繕いも外連も消えてしまうくらいに
so much that my facades and pretenses disappear,
今は触っていたいんだ 君の心に
right now, I want to be touching your heart.
僕たちは きっといつか遠く離れた
Surely one day, we will even reach out
太陽にすら手が届いて
to the distant sun,
夜明け前を手に入れて笑おう
and let's smile having seized the time before dawn.
そうやって青く燃える色に染まり
Stained in a blue-burning color like that,
おぼろげな街の向こうへ
beyond the hazy city,
手をつないで走っていけるはずだ
we should be able to run holding hands.
君と未来を盗み描く
Stealing and sketching the future with you,
捏造のないストーリーを
a story free of fabrication.
カサブタだらけ荒くれた日々が
The wild days full of scabs,
削り削られ擦り切れた今が
the present worn down and frayed,
君の言葉で蘇る
are revived by your words,
鮮やかにも現れていく
vividly coming into sight.
蛹のままで眠る魂を
The soul sleeping as a pupa,
食べかけのまま捨てたあの夢を
the dream discarded half-eaten,
もう一度取り戻せ
take them back once again!
もう一度 遠くへ行け遠くへ行けと
"Go further, go further once more,"
僕の中で誰かが歌う
someone sings inside of me,
どうしようもないほど熱烈に
so intensely that I can't help it.
いつだって目を腫らした君が二度と
So that you, who always had swollen eyes from crying,
悲しまないように笑える
can smile and never feel sad again—
そんなヒーローになるための歌
this is a song to become that kind of hero.
さらば掲げろピースサイン
Farewell, raise your peace sign
転がっていくストーリーを
to the story that keeps rolling on.
君と未来を盗み描く
Stealing and sketching the future with you,
捏造のないストーリーを
a story free of fabrication.
考えたってわからないし
Even if I think about it, I don't understand,
青空の下 君を待った
under the blue sky, I waited for you.
風が吹いた正午 昼下がりを抜け出す想像
At noon when the wind blew, imagining breaking out of early afternoon.
ねぇ これからどうなるんだろうね
Hey, I wonder what will happen from now on?
進め方教わらないんだよ
We're never taught how to move forward.
君の目を見た 何も言えず僕は歩いた
I looked into your eyes; unable to say anything, I walked on.
考えたってわからないし
Even if I think about it, I don't understand,
青春なんてつまらないし
youth is so boring anyway.
辞めたはずのピアノ 机を弾く癖が抜けない
The piano I was supposed to have quit—I can't lose the habit of playing on my desk.
ねぇ 将来何してるんだろうね
Hey, I wonder what I'll be doing in the future?
音楽はしてないといいね
It'd be nice if I wasn't making music.
困らないでよ
Don't look so troubled.
...引いても
...even if I draw a line,
どうしても消えなかった
no matter what, it wouldn't disappear.
今更なんだからな
It's too late now anyway.
思い出すな
Don't remember it.
間違ってるんだよ
You're wrong.
分かってないよ あんたら人間も
You don't get it, you humans too.
本当も愛も世界も苦しさも人生も
Truth, love, the world, pain, life...
どうでもいいよ
I don't care about any of it.
正しいかどうか知りたいのだって防衛本能だ
Wanting to know if it's right is a defense mechanism.
考えたんだ
I thought about it,
あんたのせいだ
it's your fault.
考えたってわからないが
Even if I think about it, I don't understand,
本当に年老いたくないんだ
but I really don't want to grow old.
いつか死んだらって思うだけで胸が空っぽになるんだ
Just thinking about dying someday makes my heart feel empty.
将来何してるだろって
Wondering what I'll be doing in the future...
大人になったら分かったよ
When I grew up, I understood.
何もし提案いさ
I'm not doing anything at all.
幸せな顔した人が憎いのはどう割り切ったらいいんだ
How should I make sense of hating people with happy faces?
満たされない頭の奥の化け物みたいな劣等感
The monster-like sense of inferiority deep inside my unsatisfied mind.
間違ってないよ
I'm not wrong.
なぁ なんだかんだ あんたら人間だ
Hey, after all is said and done, you're human.
愛も救いも優しさも根拠がないなんて気味が悪いよ
Love, salvation, and kindness having no basis is creepy.
ラブソングなんか痛いのだって防衛本能だ
Love songs feeling painful is just a defense mechanism.
なんだかんだだって
Whatever you say,
あんたのせいだ
it's your fault.
どうでもいいか
Does it matter?
あんたのせいだ
It's your fault.
考えたってわからないし
Even if I think about it, I don't understand,
生きてるだけでも苦しいし
and just living is painful,
音楽とかもう分からないし
and I don't even understand music anymore,
歌詞とか適当でもいいよ
and lyrics can be whatever for all I care.
どうでもいいんだ
It doesn't matter.
間違ってないだろう
I'm not wrong, right?
間違ってないよな
間違ってるんだよ
You're wrong.
分かってんだ
I know it now,
あんたら人間も
you humans too.
本当も愛も救いも優しさも人生も
Truth, love, salvation, kindness, life...
どうでもいいんだ
I don't care about any of it.
正しい答えが言えないのだって防衛本能だ
Not being able to give the right answer is a defense mechanism.
どうでもいいや
Whatever, I don't care,
あんたのせいだ
it's your fault.
僕だって信念があった
Even I had my beliefs.
今じゃゴミみたいな思い出だ
Now they're just trash-like memories.
何度でも君を書いた
I wrote about you time and time again.
売れることこそがどうでもよかったんだ
Whether it sold or not didn't matter at all.
本当だ
It's true,
本当なんだ
it's really true.
昔はそうだった
That's how it used to be.
だから僕は
That's why I...
音楽を辞めた
stopped making music.
今なんじゃない？
Isn't it now?
メラメラとたぎれ
Boil with excitement!
眠っているだけの正義
Justice that is merely sleeping.
こんな僕も
Even someone like me
君のヒーローになりたいのさ
wants to be your hero!
かっこいい君には
To the cool you,
僕じゃ頼りないのかななんて
am I unreliable, I wonder?
そりゃそうだよな だって
Well, that makes sense, because
今もこうして迷ってる
even now, I'm hesitating like this.
手を取ってくれないか
Won't you take my hand?
ギブアンドテイクさ
It's give and take.
君が僕のヒーローだったように
Just like you were my hero.
今なんじゃない？
Isn't it now?
メラメラとたぎる
Boiling with excitement,
こんな僕にも潜む正義が
the justice hidden inside someone like me.
どうしようもない衝動に駆られて
Driven by an irresistible impulse,
ほら気づけば手を握っている
look, before I know it, I'm holding your hand.
一体全体
Where on earth
そんなに荷物を背負い込んでどこへ行くの
are you going, carrying so much baggage?
ねぇねぇ待って
Hey, wait,
僕にちょっと預けてみては？
why not entrust a little bit of it to me?
信じてばかりの僕と
With me, who does nothing but believe,
信じることが怖い君と
and you, who are afraid to believe...
どちらが正しい
Which one of us is right...
のかなんて誰にも
no one really knows...
分からないさ
at all.
僕らだけの世界
A world of our own.
ギブアンドテイクさ
It's all give and take.
補い合えた暁には 同じ夢を見たい
When we complement each other, I want to dream the same dream.
君はかっこいいと 苦しめて
Calling you cool and causing you pain,
ひとりぼっちにさせたのは
leaving you all alone...
少し僕のせいなんだよな
was partly my fault, wasn't it?
ごめんね
I'm sorry.
だけど見るべきはリアルだ
But reality is what we must face.
今こそ僕が助けるんだ
Now it's my turn to save you.
抱えないで
Don't bottle it up,
信じて
trust in me,
頼ってほしいんだ
I want you to rely on me.
今なんじゃない？
Isn't now the time?
メラメラとたぎる
Burning and boiling over,
こんな僕にも潜む正義が
the sense of justice hidden even within me.
どうしようもない衝動に駆られて
Driven by an uncontrollable impulse,
ほら気が付けば手を握っている
look, before I know it, I'm holding your hand.
ほっとけない
I can't just leave you alone.
そんなに荷物を背負い込んでどこへ行くの
Carrying so much baggage, where are you going?
ほんのちょっと 僕にちょっと 預けてみては？
Why not entrust a little bit of it to me?
こんな僕も君のヒーローになりたいのさ
Even someone like me wants to be your hero.
はい！みなさん！
Hello, everyone!
とうとう始まってしまいました！
It has finally begun!
天音かなた 卒業ライブ！
Amane Kanata's Graduation Live!
と言うことでですね
So then,
こちら、ハッシュタグが
for the hashtag here,
あの、#天音かなた卒業ライブ でございますんで
it's #天音かなた卒業ライブ, so
ぜひこちら、よろしくお願いいたします
please make sure to use it!
1曲目に歌った「Mela!」は、実は初配信で歌おうか悩んでいた楽曲だったので
The first song I sang, "Mela!", was actually one I debated singing during my debut stream,
ここで歌えてすごくよかった。ありがとう！
so I'm really glad I could sing it here. Thank you!
小さい頃からね、ヒロインよりヒーローになりたいっていうタイプだったので、そういった楽曲をたくさん歌わせていただきました
Ever since I was little, I was the type who wanted to be a hero rather than a heroine, so I sang a lot of songs like that.
次からは...ありがとね、みんな。拍手ありがとう。
Starting from the next one... thank you, everyone. Thanks for the applause.
次からはロックで、感情ぶつけていくような
Next up, it's rock, pouring out my emotions...
調整しますんで
I'll adjust things,
ちょっとマイクがね、調整しますんで
my mic is a bit... I'll adjust it.
聴いてください
Please listen.
「劣等上等」！
"BRING IT ON"!
劣等上等
BRING IT ON
劣等上等 BRING IT ON
Bring it on, bring it on
列島上々 不眠日本
Island nation jumping, sleepless Japan
子供騙しのマセマティカ
Childish mathematics
ご立派 警鐘 気取りで
Acting like a grand warning bell
高みの見物ばかりじゃ つまんねぇ
Just watching from high up is so boring.
ほらもっと 間違って上等
Come on, making more mistakes is just fine!
退屈に手をかけて
Killing off the boredom,
こんなところじゃ 終われない
I can't end in a place like this.
ぬるくて気が触れそう
It's so lukewarm I'm going crazy.
ごっこ遊びも芝居もさよなら
Goodbye to make-believe and acting.
ダッダッダ あたし大人になる
Da-da-da, I'm growing up!
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて今
Experiencing both the sweet and the sour now.
パッパッパ 変わる時代
Pa-pa-pa, changing times!
悪いことばかりじゃないでしょう
It's not all bad, right?
過去も、罪も、罰も、すべて
The past, the sins, the punishment, everything...
素手で、愛で 生き抜いてやり返すわ
Bare-handed, with love, I'll survive and strike back!
yeah, 挑発 あたしたちは no doubt
Yeah, provocation, we're no doubt!
緑のあいつにばっか構ってんね
Just obsessing over that green one, huh?
さぁ burn up
Come on, burn up!
いつになったら貰える合格
When am I gonna get a passing grade?
赤ペン入れてよ どこがダメなんですか
Mark it with a red pen, what's wrong with it?
酒女金ドラッグ やっっちゃってコンプラ
Booze, girls, money, drugs, violating compliance!
冗談じゃないって
You gotta be kidding me
中指立てたくなるような事情
So many situations make me wanna raise my middle finger
ありすぎて指が足りねぇから
I don't have enough fingers for them all, so...
Hands up and what's up
最低？
The absolute worst?
元々だろ Bring it on
I was like that from the start! Bring it on!
ママ、やっぱりあたしは
Mama, as I thought, I...
こんなところじゃ終われない
...can't end in a place like this!
ぬるくて気が触れそう
It's so lukewarm I'm losing my mind
ごっこ遊びも芝居もさよなら
Goodbye to playing pretend and acting!
ずっとこのままなんてさぁ いられないよ
I can't just stay like this forever!
ダッダッダッ 僕ら大人になる
Da-da-da, we're gonna grow up
カウンター狙い
Aiming for a counterattack,
最低な日々に
At these terrible days,
燦々とかます一撃
Striking a brilliant blow,
誰も読めない先まで
Far beyond what anyone can predict!
決まってんでしょ？
Isn't that obvious?
いつも
Always,
どれも
Everything,
捨てて 捨てて
Throwing it all away,
生きて 生き抜いて覆すわ
Surviving and turning it all around!
ダッダッ くだらない
Da-da, so foolish,
言葉ばっかが譲れない
These endless words I won't yield.
わかるか？ あたしの美学
Do you get it? My aesthetic.
この馬鹿正直な拳ひとつが
This single, foolishly honest fist...
一途なんです
...is earnest,
切り札
My trump card...
愚直なんです
...is straightforward,
がなる劣等
Roaring out my inferiority,
一抜けよ さらば！
Bowing out first, farewell!
こんなもんじゃない
I'm not done yet!
ダッダッダッ あたし大人になる
Da-da-da, I'm gonna grow up
燦々と交わる未来
Into a brilliantly intersecting future!
もう子供じゃないのわかるでしょう
You can tell I'm not a child anymore, right?
燦々交わる未来
A brilliantly intersecting future!
時代 機会 待ってくれない
Era and opportunity won't wait for us
素手で 捨て身で 生き抜いて上等だわ
Bare-handed, risking it all, surviving is top-tier!
それでは皆様 お先に Bye guys!
Well then, everyone, bye guys!
フロアが湧き上がりました
The floor has gone wild!
ぼくらの16bit戦争
[Title: Our 16bit War]
どうしてこんなことになったんだ？
How did things end up like this?
誰も教えてくれないんだ
Nobody will tell me.
何が正義だ
What is justice?
何が犠牲だ
What is sacrifice?
秩序は僕を裏切った
"Order" betrayed me.
初めは小さな穴だったんだ
At first, it was just a tiny hole.
居心地だけは良かったのにな
Even though it was so comfortable.
プロパガンダと飲めや歌えや
With propaganda, drinking, and singing,
穴は次第に誇大化した
The hole gradually grew massive.
相対と絶対の飽和水蒸気圧
Saturated vapor pressure of relative and absolute...
都合が善過ぎた大人達の都合に
...suited the convenient adults far too well.
ひとつまたひとつと未来は
One by one, the future...
過去を無視した
...ignored the past.
65535のテトラと
With 65,535 tetraminos
ゼロ次元の理想
And zero-dimensional ideals,
抱えていてもなお
Even while holding onto them,
ひとつまたひとつとエデンは
One by one, Eden...
姿を消した
...vanished from sight.
ぼくらの16bit戦争
Our 16bit War!
イデアの波に蝕まれるな
Don't be consumed by the waves of ideas.
残された空間で
In the remaining space,
僕はおかつに肘さえつけやしない
I can't even rest my elbow carelessly.
ぼくらの16bit戦争
Our 16bit War!
アルトとエゴが交差する
Alto and ego intersect.
XYしか愛せない
Loving only X and Y,
僕は何を信じて生きればいい？
What should I believe in to live?
どっと包囲網をかいくぐり
Ducking through the sudden encirclement,
レジスタンスら一斉照射
The resistance opens fire all at once.
無言 圧力 数暴力
Silent pressure, violence of numbers,
自由はすでになくなった
Freedom is already gone.
ハガネに打ち込めよと
"Strike into the steel!"
鴻鵠の警笛
The whistle of the swan,
肩越しに響く矩形波
square waves echoing over my shoulder,
成る断末
making up my dying moments.
アルカディアの鐘が鳴る日は来るのだろうか？
Will the day ever come when Arcadia's bells toll?
ぼくらの16bit戦争
Our 16-bit war.
イデアの波に蝕まれるな
Don't be consumed by the waves of ideas.
残された空間で僕は
In this leftover space,
今日もぐっすり眠れやしない
I can't sleep soundly again today.
ぼくらの16bit戦争
Our 16-bit war.
アルトとエゴが交差する
Where altruism and ego intersect,
リットダウン ビットレートの積で
at the product of bit rate and reduction,
僕は秩序を裏切らない
I will not betray order.
ぼくらの16bit戦争
Our 16-bit war.
世界を敵に回しても
Even if I turn the whole world into my enemy,
表現し得ないものが
having what cannot be expressed
縛られることが何より許せなかった
bound was what I couldn't forgive above all.
ぼくらの16bit戦争
Our 16-bit war.
はい！
Yes!
皆さんありがとうございます！
Thank you so much, everyone!
ここにね 何があると思います？
What do you think is over here?
水
Water.
今回は歌に集中するラインナップで来ましたけれど
This time I came with a lineup focusing on singing, but...
トレンド1位って本当ですかこれ？
Is it really true that we're #1 trending?
嘘かもしれませんけれど...本当かな？
It might be a lie, but... is it real?
ガチかも！
It might actually be real!
ありがとうみんな！
Thank you, everyone!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
かっこいいと言ってくれているのを見ながら...
As I was reading everyone saying it's cool...
メガホンマイクが手からすっぽ抜けかけましたよ
the megaphone mic almost slipped right out of my hand!
本当に焦ったわ
I really panicked there!
ということでね、えーっと...
So anyway, um...
何かに挑んでいく曲みたいなのは好きなので元々
I've always loved songs about standing up to a challenge,
『劣等上等』と『ぼくらの16bit戦争』を歌わせていただきました！
so I sang "BRING IT ON" and "Our 16bit Wars"!
すごい大好きなかっこいい楽曲たちなので
They're super cool songs that I absolutely love,
ぜひぜひ原曲もチェックしてみてください！
so please go check out the original songs too!
ちょっ... ちょっと待って
W-Wait a second.
僕VTuberなんで着替えは何秒かかると思う？
Since I'm a VTuber, how many seconds do you think changing outfits takes?
1秒で！
Just one second!
これ！
Look at this!
すごいだろ？
Amazing, right?
これがVTuber、バーチャルアイドルね！
That's a VTuber, a virtual idol for you!
ではこのまま続けていくぞー！
Now then, let's keep going!
ローリンガール
Rolling Girl
ロンリーガールはいつまでも
The lonely girl is always
届かない夢見て
dreaming unreachable dreams,
騒ぐ頭の中をかき回して
churning through the noise inside her head,
かき回して
churning through it.
「問題ない。」とつぶやいて
"No problem," she mutters,
言葉は失われた？
but have her words been lost?
もう失敗、もう失敗
Failed again, failed again.
間違い探しの終われば また回るの！
End up looking for mistakes, and it spins again!
もう一回、もう一回
One more time, one more time.
「私は今日も転がります。」と
"I'll keep rolling again today,"
少女は言う 少女は言う
the girl says, the girl says,
言葉に意味を奏でながら！
playing meaning into her words!
「もう良いかい？」
"Are you good now?"
「まだですよ、まだまだ先は見えないので。
"Not yet, I still can't see what lies ahead.
息を止めるの、今。」
Holding my breath, right now."
ローリンガールの成れの果て
The end result of the rolling girl,
届かない、向こうの色
colors beyond her reach.
重なる声と混ぜ合わせ て 混ぜ合わせて
Blending together with overlapping voices, blending together.
「問題ない。」と呟いた言葉は失われた
"I'm fine," she muttered, but her words were lost.
どうなったっていいんだってさ
Saying she didn't care what happened anymore.
間違いだって起こしちゃおうと誘う坂道
On an uphill slope that invites her to make mistakes.
もう一回、もう一回
One more time, one more time.
私をどうか転がしてと 少女は言う 少女は言う
"Please roll me along," the girl says, the girl says.
無口に意味を重ねながら！
Layering meaning into her silence!
「もう良いかい？」
"Are you ready yet?"
「もう少し、もうすぐ何か見えるだろうと。息を止めるの、今。」
"Just a bit more. We'll see something soon. Hold your breath, for now."
もう一回、もう一回
One more time, one more time.
「私は今日も転がります。」と 少女は言う 少女は言う
"I'll roll along again today," the girl says, the girl says.
言葉に意味を奏でながら！
Playing meaning into her words!
「もう良いかい？ もう良いよ。そろそろ君も疲れたろう、ね。」
"Are you ready yet? That's enough now. You must be tired by now, right?"
息を止めるの、今。
Stop breathing, for now.
今度こそ 生き返れない そう思った ベッドの中
In my bed, I thought, "This time, I won't survive."
気づけばカーテンの隙間から 朝が正解を教えた
Before I knew it, morning through the curtains showed me the answer.
ああ 生きてたと安堵
Ah, relieved that I was alive.
ああ 生きてしまったと絶望
Ah, in despair that I had survived.
まだやれるのかな まだやらなきゃいけないのかな
Can I still keep going? Do I still have to keep going?
いっそ放り投げてしまえば
If I just threw it all away...
なんてね
Just kidding.
「僕は元気です」 そう言って今日も笑って
"I'm doing fine," I say with a smile again today.
心はガラガラと 大げさな音がする
My heart makes an exaggerated, rattling noise.
ああ 終末の鐘の音か
Ah, is that the sound of the end bells?
それでもこの声か
Even so, with this voice?
それでもこの口か
Even so, with this mouth?
それでもこの喉か
Even so, with this throat?
ちぎれるくらい 叫ぶよ
I'll scream until it tears apart.
この歌か 真白なこの羽が
With this song, with these pure white wings,
僕のこの命が
this life of mine...
生きたいと歌っている
is singing that it wants to live.
感情の捨て方はさ
How to throw away emotions?
粗大ゴミのシールを貼る
Just stick an oversized trash sticker on them.
本音はいつも強がりの裏 潰れてる音がするんだ
My true feelings behind my tough facade make a crushing noise.
ああ 気づかれなかった
Ah, no one noticed.
ああ 気づいてほしいんだ
Ah, I want someone to notice.
それでも君が笑ってくれるなら
But if you can smile for me,
いっそ心を無くしてしまえば
maybe I should just lose my heart altogether...
なんてね
Just kidding.
叶わないなんて 一瞬でも思ったら負けだ
If I think it won't come true for even a second, I lose.
叶わないなんて 一瞬でもよぎったらやめだ
If the thought even crosses my mind for a second, it's over.
何万回の諦める理由があったとしても
Even if there are tens of thousands of reasons to give up,
たった一つの 勇気はこの手の中に
just one piece of courage is right here in my hands.
それでもこの声か
Even so, with this voice?
それでもこの口か
Even so, with this mouth?
それでもこの喉か
Even so, with this throat?
ちぎれるくらい 叫ぶよ
I'll scream until it tears apart.
出来るなら愛されたい 許されたい ここにいたい 愛したい
If possible, I want to be loved, forgiven, stay here, and love.
誰も見ていない夢を見ろよ だから僕を見ろよ
Dream a dream no one is watching, so look at me!
誰も見てない 夢を見せるよ だから
I'll show you a dream no one has seen before, so...
僕を信じて
Believe in me.
はい！
All right!
皆さん！ 今のは最後のオリジナル楽曲です！
Everyone! That was my final original song!
『誰も見てない夢を見ろ』というね、本日24時にリリース！
"Dare mo Mitenai Yume wo Miro", which will be released at midnight tonight!
わー！ こちらのジャケット...
Wow! Look at this cover art...
を頼りに配信を探してくださいね
Please use this as a guide to search for it on streaming platforms!
この曲、あまりにも卒業ソングすぎるって思ったでしょう？
You might think this song sounds way too much like a graduation song, right?
これ実は卒業を決める前に作られていた曲で
This song was actually created before my graduation was decided!
MVは明日ね
The MV will go live tomorrow,
明日の20時、もうかなたそがいなくなっても予約投稿というものがあるネットには
at 8 PM tomorrow! Even after I'm gone, scheduled uploads exist on the internet!
ということで明日の20時に投稿されるんですが
So it will be posted tomorrow at 8 PM,
内容も実は卒業を誰も知らずに作っているということで
and the content was actually made without anyone knowing about my graduation.
こんな偶然の一致でそれっぽくなってしまいました
Through such a coincidence, it ended up fitting so perfectly.
それを踏まえて「なんでやねん」と思いながら聴いてください
Keeping that in mind, please listen to it while thinking, "How did that happen?!"
樋口愛さんに作詞作曲していただいて
Written and composed by Ai Higuchi-san,
あの『悪魔の子』ね、いっぱい歌ったりしたんで
since I've sung "Akuma no Ko" so many times!
超嬉しかったです！ ありがとうございます！
I was super happy! Thank you so much!
そしてですね、お次はグッズをご紹介させていただきます！ こちら！
And next, let me introduce the merch! Right here!
はい！ 天音かなた卒業グッズがもう出てます！ なんと出ている！
Yes! The Amane Kanata Graduation Merch is already available! Believe it or not!
ということでそれでは一つずつ見ていきましょう！ まずはこちら！
So let's take a look at them one by one! First up is this!
はい！ アクリルパネルです！ 可愛いでしょう！
Yes! The acrylic panel! Isn't it cute?
じゃーん！
Tada!
こちらね、お塩ママに想いをお伝えした上で描き下ろしていただいたイラストになっております
This is a new illustration drawn by Oshio-mama after I shared my thoughts with her.
本当にね、みんなに対して最後はまあ笑顔かなとか、青い薔薇というものをね
I thought a smile for everyone at the end would be best, and blue roses...
最初からちょっとモチーフ的に入れたりすることがあったので
...were something I've used as a motif since the beginning,
こちらでまた入れていただきました。可愛いでしょう！
so she included them here again. Cute, right?
笑顔にしてもらいました！
I asked her to give me a big smile!
お次はこちら！ じゃーん！
Next is this! Tada!
かなた＆こなた アクリルスタンドです！
The Kanata & Konata acrylic stand!
これもね、僕が本当にこなたという妹というものをぜひこのように残して
I really wanted to preserve my little sister, Konata, like this,
「生きてえよ」ということで、僕が欲しいがために生まれたグッズでございます！
so I could say "I want to keep her alive!" It's merch born purely because I wanted it myself!
可愛いでしょう！
Isn't it cute?
エロいよな... ということでお次はこちら！
It's kinda spicy, right...? Anyway, next up is this!
じゃーん！
Tada!
ボイスキーホルダーです！
The Voice Keychain!
ボイスの6種は僕がオリジナル考えました。オリジナルっつっても「へーい」
I thought up the 6 voice lines myself! Though by original I mean lines like "Hey,"
「こんかなたー」とかだけどさ。じゃーん！
"Konkanata~" and stuff. Tada!
で、このイラストもですね、僕原案を描いてプロがすごい良くしてくれましたね
And for this illustration, I drew the draft and a pro made it look amazing!
でも分かるでしょう？ かなたその絵柄って。皆さんありがとうございました
But you can tell it's Kanata's art style, right? Thank you, everyone!
収録ボイスは届いてからのお楽しみです！ いっぱいポチポチしてください！
Look forward to the voice lines when it arrives! Press it lots!
そして最後のグッズはこちら！ じゃじゃーん！
And the final merch item is this! Ta-da!
『あるてぃめっとへい民 認定証』！
The "Ultimate Hey-min Certificate"!
これは最後まで応援してくれた究極のへい民
This is a certificate for the ultimate Hey-min who supported me till the very end,
アルティメットへい民の認定証です。シリアルナンバーが入っていて世界で1枚です
the Ultimate Hey-min! It has a serial number and is unique in the world!
ちなみにちょっと... お買い得じゃねえや（笑）
By the way, it's pretty... wait, not "a bargain"! (laughs)
手が届きやすいので、これだけでもぜひ皆さん
It's easy to get, so even if it's just this, everyone,
思い出によろしくお願いします！
please get it as a keepsake!
「今までへい民じゃなかったけどかなたー」って思った人もね
Even if you weren't a Hey-min before, if you feel like "Kanata~",
アルティメットへい民だから！ あんたは！
you're an Ultimate Hey-min! Yes, you!
ということでですね、お次はこちら特典ですね！
So then, next we have the purchase bonus!
はい、特典はポストカードになっております！
Yes, the bonus item is a postcard!
数量限定が直筆サイン入りだったんですが
The limited quantity version includes a hand-signed autograph,
こちらは12月24日の8時から発売開始しており
and went on sale starting at 8 PM on December 24th,
もう... 品切れ！ ごめんなさい、完売しているんですけど
and it's already... sold out! Sorry, it sold out,
フルセットの方はまだありますので
but the full set version is still available,
箔押し複製サイン入ってますので、よろしくお願いします！
and features a foil-stamped signature, so please check it out!
ちょっとね、このフルセット特典の方は
The full set bonus postcard...
「寂しいよ」っていう気持ちがちょっと溢れ出た、ドゥルルって感じになっております！
has a bit of an overflowing "I'm lonely" vibe to it!
はい、ぜひよろしくお願いします！
Yes, please support it!
ふう... すげえ... 汗が...
Phew... Wow... I'm sweating...
かなたちゃん！ サプライズ！
Kanata-chan! Surprise!
サプライズできました！
We managed to surprise you!
えー！ かなたー！ ひでえよー！ 辞めさせてー！
Eh?! Kanata~! That's so cruel! Let me retire!
え、ゲストいないので...
Eh? There are no guests, so...
卒業辞めさせないよ！ 寂しいだろ、一人で卒業なんて！ 見送るよ！
We won't let you retire! Graduating alone is so lonely! We're here to see you off!
あっと... 来て... ああ出てる！ 出てる！
Ah... they came... Ah, they're showing up! They're on screen!
ころさん、ラミ子、みこちゃんがなんか... 来てくれました！
Koro-san, Ramiko, and Miko-chan came!
歌うまくなったねー！ / ええっ！ ありがとう！
You've gotten so good at singing! / Eh?! Thank you!
えー！
Eh?!
ちょっと私たちからは渡したいものがありますよね。
Wait, we have something we want to give you, right?
なになになに？マジで聞いてない、知らない！
What, what, what? Really? I didn't hear about this! I don't know!
マジで言ってない、マジで言ってない！
We really didn't tell you, really didn't tell you!
なんか嫌だー！
Wait, no way~!
泣かせないで、ねぇ！
Don't make me cry, hey!
かなたー！
Kanata~!
はい、どうぞー！
Here you go!
ありがとう！持てないか、持てないよね？
Thank you! Can't hold it, you can't hold it right?
あ、すごい！
Ah, amazing!
これ3人で選んだ...
The three of us picked this...
花束だ！
A bouquet!
お花です！
It's flowers!
え、すごい！なんかとっても美しいバラみたいな感じの...
Ehh, amazing! It's like... really beautiful roses...
ちょっとバーチャル空間には映らないんだけど...
Though it doesn't show up in the virtual space...
ちょっと映らないんですけど、僕だけのものです、みんな！
It doesn't show on screen, but this is mine alone, everyone!
え、すごい！こんなにでかい花束もらったことない！
Eh, amazing! I've never gotten such a huge bouquet!
一旦回収しまーす。
I'll collect it for now~
はい、すみません、ありがとうございます。
Yes, sorry, thank you so much.
それね、3人で寄せ書きしまして...
Also, the three of us wrote a message board...
えー！まじですか？！ありがとう！
Ehh?! Really?! Thank you!
しまった、今見たら泣いちゃう...
Oh no, if I look now I'll cry...
泣いちゃうね。
You'll cry.
泣いちゃう！また後でありがとうございます！
I'll cry! Thank you, I'll read it again later!
いや待って本当に嫌だ、本当に嫌だ、嫌だー！
Wait, I really hate this! I really hate this! No~
やめろー！
Stop it!
やめるの？やめるの？
Are you quitting? Are you quitting?
ここで？ここでここで？
Here? Here, here?
ここでやめて大炎上...
Quitting here would cause a huge scandal...
だっていいよね？今から3人分も背負ってくれるってことで...
Because it's fine, right? Since she's going to carry our parts for three people too...
少々、少々よ！
A little bit, just a little!
心強い！
How reassuring!
再配信、明日初配信...
Re-stream, tomorrow's first stream...
再配信、明日ね！
Re-stream tomorrow!
切り替えて初配信しよう！
Let's reset and do a debut stream!
切り替えていくかー！
Time to reset!
いやーありがとうみんなー！嬉しい！
Ah, thank you everyone~! I'm so happy!
めちゃめちゃ頼んだの、会いに来たいって。
I begged so hard saying I wanted to come see you.
そうなの？！
Really?!
もう1人で...なんか勝手に色んなものさ、背負ってさ...
She was just on her own... carrying all sorts of things on her shoulders...
そうだよ！
That's right!
やめて行くなんて許せない！
Quitting and leaving, we won't allow it!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
逃がさない！頼れよもっと！頼れ！周りを頼れ！頼れ頼れ！
We won't let you escape! Rely on us more! Rely! Rely on those around you! Rely, rely!
ありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you!
あとでもうちょっと無理を言ーって、今日駆けつけさせていただきました！
Even later, ask for the unreasonable... We rushed over here today!
本当に、本当に、本当にすごいこと！ありがとうね！
Really, really, really amazing thing! Thank you!
最後まで見るからね！
We'll watch until the end!
見てるからね！
We're watching!
え、行っちゃうの？
Eh, are you leaving?
行かない！お前だよ行くのは！
Not us! You're the one who's going!
あ、僕が行くんだ！
Ah, I'm the one going!
お前が行くんだよ！お前が行くんだよ！
You're the one going! You're the one going!
先に行くんだ！
Going on ahead!
行っちゃうのじゃないの！
It's not "are you leaving"!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
行かない、見てるからね！ずっと見てるよ！
Not going, we're watching! We're watching all the time!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
頑張ってね！最後まで！
Do your best! Until the very end!
まだ泣かないよ、まだあるからね！
Don't cry yet, there's still more!
あとで観に来てんのね今、本当に！
They came to watch later, really!
頼むよー！
I'm begging you~
頑張れー！頑張ってね！
Do your best! Good luck!
ありがとうね！これからもずっと仲良くしてください！
Thank you! Please keep being good friends with me from now on too!
当たり前じゃん！
Of course!
一生友達だよね！一生友達！一生友達！
Friends for life, right? Friends for life! Friends for life!
ずっと、これからも先もずっとだからね！
Forever, from now on and in the future too!
当たり前だよ！
Of course!
縁側で語り明かそうね！
Let's talk all night on the porch!
おばあちゃんになってもね！
Even when we're old grandmas!
そこで見ているから！
We'll be watching right there!
うん、ありがとう！
Yeah, thank you!
頑張れー！大好きだぞー！
Do your best! Love you!
大好き！大好きだよ！
Love you! Love you too!
愛してる！頑張ってね！
Love you! Good luck!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
またね！
See you!
またね！またね！
See you! See you!
今回、みんなに説明した感じで、ゲストは今回は呼べないけど頑張るよって言ってたんですけど...
This time, as I explained to everyone, I said I couldn't invite guests this time but would do my best, but...
コロさんとアズちゃんとルイ美が来てくれました。本当にありがとうございます。
Korone-san, Az-chan, and Luimy came for me. Thank you so very much.
それでは... ここから...
Well then... from here on...
オリジナル楽曲が続いていきます。歌えるのはね、最後になってしまうんですが、だからこそ沢山の思い出を思い出しながら心込めて歌っていこうと思います。
A sequence of original songs will follow. Singing them... this will be the last time, which is precisely why I want to sing each one with all my heart while recalling so many memories.
ちょっと... びっくりした...
I was... a little surprised...
本当にありがとう。本当に素晴らしい友達を持てて幸せです。ホロライブに入れてよかった。
Thank you so much. I'm so happy to have such wonderful friends. I'm so glad I joined Hololive.
ということで、じゃあ、聞いてね！
And with that, please listen!
キミのきゅーぴっとです。
I'm your Cupid.
夢中 夢中 きっと夢に出てくる
Obsessed, obsessed, I'm sure I'll appear in your dreams
ちゅっちゅちゅっちゅ ちゅっちゅちゅっちゅ ちゅっちゅちゅっちゅ
Chu chu chu chu, chu chu chu chu, chu chu chu chu
きゅっと抱きしめて！
Hold me tight!
急に鳴った着信音 (ヤダヤダヤダヤダ)
Sudden ringtone (No no no no)
強制トークの床屋さん (ヤダヤダヤダヤダ)
Barber shop with forced small talk (No no no no)
誰かが待ってるエレベーター (ヤダヤダヤダヤダ)
An elevator where someone is waiting (No no no no)
そう 我らこそ“陰の者”
Yes, we are the "Introverts"
笑おう 笑おう せめて笑おう
Let's smile, let's smile, at least let me smile
あはは うぇへへ なるほどです
Ahaha, uehehe, I see how it is
口内 口内 乾きまくり
My mouth, my mouth is completely dry
反省 反省 また反省だ
Regret, regret, regret all over again
鏡ですらも目を逸らした
I even averted my eyes from the mirror
明日は今日より人間になりたい...
Tomorrow I want to be human more than today...
なりたい！なりたい！なりたい！
I want to be! I want to be! I want to be!
おやすみさん
Good night
Even the number 1 performance from now
私ちっとも物足りんじゃないのに
Although I'm not unsatisfied at all...
まぁ愚かでゾンビの可愛さね ここでしょね
Ah, the foolishness of zombies is cute, isn't it? Right here, right?
あー あなたに捧げるわ 私の愛とやらスベテ
Ah, I'll dedicate everything—my "love" or whatever it is—to you.
この手は私を守るためあったのね
These hands existed just to protect me, didn't they?
救い気取りはどんな作用だらけ？
What kind of effects does acting like a savior bring?
レストはうんとかざらなきゃ
I have to put on a grand rest...
ちょっと一切だって ちょっと少しだけ
Even just a little, even just a tiny bit...
DA・LI・LA 赤もキレイ
DA・LI・LA, even the red is beautiful.
十万億土
[Title: Ten Trillion Pure Lands]
最上抜け出し死ぬ気でみな暴れ
Escape the top tier, everyone go wild like your life depends on it!
倒れ奴隷と化す手形の手
Hands stamped, collapsed and turned into slaves.
歳の賽は流されたのでしょう さいよさいよどうもこうもない
The die of age has been cast, there's no helping it now!
弱者隔離よ こちらへおいでよ
Quarantine of the weak, come over here!
鏡を騙す人は誰？
Who is the person deceiving the mirror?
恐れず僕の選択を
Without fear, make my choice!
パッパッパのパッパッパ パッパッパのパッパッパ
Pa-pa-pa no pa-pa-pa, pa-pa-pa no pa-pa-pa!
巡り巡る隔離の世 映し出そう
Let's reflect this revolving world of quarantine.
そろそろ終わりにしないか
Isn't it time to end this?
今ならば愛しいほうら
If it's now, it's lovely, look...
君は今更もう戻れない
You can no longer go back after all this time.
別世界
[Title: Another World]
愛してくれ僕のことも どうか邪魔などしないでから
Love me too, please don't get in my way...
遠い遠い別世界まで
All the way to a distant, far-off another world...
それ触れないままに幕が上がる
Without ever touching it, the curtain rises.
ただまた逢いたくてあなたに この拍手を
I just wanted to see you again; give this applause to you...
Knock it out!
[Title: Knock it out!]
無敵な Eye Eye Eye Eye 時代な キカザレほら Sweet Trendy
Invincible eye-eye-eye-eye era, dress up now, sweet trendy!
気持ちは Dai-Dai-Dai-Dine-Dine 意味ないな Dash! Show Time!
Feeling like dy-dy-dy-dying, it's meaningless! Dash! Show time!
壊せ Pride!
Break that pride!
おらくる
[Title: Oracle]
ああ あんまりあんまりもうそう 泣き言付けたりしないで
Ah, don't go making so many whining excuses...
こんなバグだらけの世界になっちゃってごめんね
Sorry that the world turned out full of bugs like this.
大丈夫 安全圏によね
It's okay, we're in the safe zone, right?
安心な世界に行こうね 見捨てないからずっと今日も
Let's go to a peaceful world; I won't abandon you, today or ever.
あらあら神様見て ただ希望になれ
Oh my, look, God—just become our hope!
根本的な線になるまで 愛下げろね
Until it becomes a fundamental line, lower your love.
どんどん余計な味足して 雑に肥大化して
Keep adding unnecessary flavors, sloppily bloating up...
忘れちゃうくらい 笑っちゃうくらい
So much you forget, so much you laugh...
探す I I I LOVE YOU
Searching for I, I, I LOVE YOU!
息を殺せ 音を立てるな 奴らに気づかれる前に
Hold your breath, don't make a sound, before they notice us.
爪を研ぎ その時を待て すべては一瞬のために
Sharpen your claws and wait for that moment; everything is for a single instant.
覚悟しろ 最後の敵は 怯え続ける自分だ
Prepare yourself, the final enemy is your cowardly self.
世界を変える劇薬は今
The powerful drug to change the world is now...
仮面の裏のアイドル 狂気と覚悟で貫け
The idol behind the mask—pierce through with madness and resolve!
泥を舐めても 絶望の果て 壊滅の最前線
Even if licking the dirt, at the end of despair, on the front lines of destruction,
地にも潜る覚悟で 忍び足じゃいられないなら
Prepared to crawl underground, if you can't tiptoe any longer!
刹那 泣き顔
In an instant, a tearful face...
すべてをこの一瞬に賭けて放て Last-resort
Stake everything on this single moment and release Last-resort!
僕のすべてを込めて放つ Last-resort
Unleashing Last-resort with all my heart!
あなたがくれた希望で
With the hope you gave me,
約束の羽で今
With the promised wings, now...
片羽
[Title: One Wing]
Ah... 世界の先へ
Ah... beyond the world.
壊れるまで高く高く
Higher and higher until I break.
今の僕は片翼でいい
The current me is fine with just one wing.
飛べるよ 信じて 飛べるよ その先へ 飛べる
I can fly, believe me, I can fly... beyond!
楽園 永遠の彼方まで ああ
To paradise, to the ends of eternity, ah...
きっと勝手 だけど
I know it's selfish, but...
遥か彼方 待って...
So far away, wait for me...
思い出して 出会った日のこと
Remember the day we first met
手をとって 僕らの旅が始まった
Taking hands, our journey began
走って転んで 涙を流しても
Even if we ran, stumbled, and shed tears
気がつけばほら 顔合わせて笑う
Before we knew it, look, we're laughing face-to-face
喜びの声が嬉しくて 夢があふれだすね
Hearing your joyful voices makes me happy, dreams overflow
君がいなきゃダメなんだ
I can't do this without you
今世界で一番幸せなアイドルから
From the happiest idol in the world right now
世界で一番の笑顔をあげちゃう
I'll give you the greatest smile in the world
僕を見つけてくれた 愛してくれたから
Because you found me and loved me
まだまだ終わらない
It's far from over yet
ちゃんとついてきて
Make sure to follow me
叶えてく夢
The dreams we'll bring to life
羽ばたいてゆく 背中を見送った
I watched your back as you fluttered away
雨上がり 君の傘を返したら
After the rain, when I return your umbrella
手を引いて進もう 一緒にどこまでも
Let's walk hand in hand, together anywhere
気がつけばほら また前を向ける
Before we know it, look, we can face forward again
じゃれ合う言葉の中に 愛を感じています
In our playful words, I feel love
僕じゃなきゃダメなんでしょ？ でしょ？
It has to be me, right? Right?
今世界で一番幸せなアイドルから
From the happiest idol in the world right now
世界で一番のときめきをあげちゃう
I'll give you the world's greatest excitement
僕を支えてくれた 推してくれたから
Because you supported me and cheered for me
まだまだ終わらない
It's far from over yet
隣にいてよ
Stay by my side
自信なんかない 不安ばっかり
I have no confidence, full of anxiety
もうやめようって 泣いた日もあった
There were days I cried, wanting to quit
そんなとき浮かんでくるの みんなの声が
In those moments, everyone's voices come to mind
今までで一番諦めたくないの
More than ever before, I don't want to give up
ずっとかなりたかった 最強のアイドル
The ultimate idol I always wanted to become
今世界で一番幸せなアイドルから
From the happiest idol in the world right now
世界で一番の「大好き」をあげちゃう
I'll give you the greatest "I love you" in the world
些細な日常も もっと大きなステージも
Both trifling everyday life and much bigger stages
まだまだ終われない
It can't end just yet
ありふれた奇跡を 君と結んでく
Connecting everyday miracles together with you
行けー！
Go!
ノンフィクション おバカ思考
Nonfiction silly thinking
ツッコミもされて 本日開店 騒ごう
Getting teased too, open today, let's make noise
ボリュームマシ 手にするぜ Everything
Max out the volume, I'll grasp everything
イッツマイライフ 狂って狂って適当に頑張ろっと
It's my life, crazy, crazy, I'll do my best in my own way
そんなんだっていいけどさ
Even if it's like that, it's fine
必死に頑張ろっと
I'll give it my absolute best
それが僕らしいのさ
That's just like me
ドサクサじゃないんだわ
It's not just a mess of chaos,
そんでぼっちじゃないんだわ
and I'm definitely not all alone!
順風満帆がバッチリ生きてるに決まってる
You know I'm living smoothly and smoothly thriving!
かなたちゃん
Kanata-chan!
現状維持とちゃんと歓迎して
Welcome maintaining the status quo,
高まりかい？ 理想像ちゃんと共感して
Feeling hyped? Empathize with the ideal image!
興奮しよう
Let's get excited!
僕が言ったんだもん
Because I said so,
誇る姿勢なんだもん
and it's a stance to be proud of!
現実超えろ未来
Beyond reality, into the future!
弱点もへっちゃら スイッチで出ちゃう
Weaknesses are no problem, toggled with a switch!
すなわち特者生存ワンダラダー
That is, special survival Wander-la-der!!
楽しもう
Let's enjoy it!
面白がれること探し構えオーライ
Find things to have fun with, ready, all right!
返事きかせてくれ
Let me hear your response!
右左どこじゃない
Left or right doesn't matter,
突き抜けて straight
Break right through, straight!
つまりたくらんだら発進 All right!
So once planned, launch! All right!
ワクワク進展中
Excitement in progress!
聞いて！みんなと離れるのが寂しいのと
Listen! I was sad about being away from everyone,
ガッキーの結婚から立ち直ってません！
and I still haven't recovered from Gakki's marriage!
僕をアイドルにしてくれてみんな本当にありがとう！
Thank you all so much for making me an idol!
なんだよそんなこと言っちゃダメだおバカ！
What's with that? You shouldn't say things like that, dummy!
うわあすごい！ありがとう！
Wow, amazing! Thank you!
Be colorful, so then go my way
虎視眈々でいたいんだもん だって勢い強行いいんだもん
I want to stay vigilant, because bold momentum is good!
全方位でがっつり 大勢の果てになっちゃう
Fully in all directions, reaching the bounds of the crowd!
いつでも心はちゃんと17歳です
In my heart, I am always properly 17 years old!
一体な portable, 忙しい毎日に死んで
An all-in-one portable, worn out by busy days,
一体になって言い聞かせるんだ
As one, I tell myself...
調子に乗ったの？
Did I get carried away?
すぐあきられちゃうから
Because people will get tired of me soon.
快感なロボットの行動ですって
They say it's the pleasant movement of a robot!
すなわち特者生存ワンダラダー
That is, special survival Wander-la-der!!
しがみつけ 努力とは
Cling onto it! What is effort?
最後まであきらめないこと
It's not giving up until the very end.
目瞑っておいて 本当は baby 自信がないよ
Keep your eyes closed; actually, baby, I have no confidence.
本当は baby 不安ばっかで泣きそうだって
Honestly, baby, I'm full of anxiety and about to cry.
ごね baby くじけないって決めたの
Pout, baby! I decided not to give up.
だから baby 挑戦したいよ 未開の地 無限の speed で
So baby, I want to challenge uncharted lands at infinite speed!
行くよ！
Here I go!
現状維持とちゃんと歓迎して
Welcome maintaining the status quo,
高まりかい？ 理想像ちゃんと共感して
Feeling hyped? Empathize with the ideal image!
興奮しよう 僕が言ったんだもん 本当にするんだもん
Let's get excited! Because I said so, and I'll really do it!
現実超えろ未来
Beyond reality, into the future!
弱点もへっちゃら スイッチで出ちゃう
Weaknesses are no problem, toggled with a switch!
すなわち特者生存ワンダラダー
That is, special survival Wander-la-der!!
楽しもう 面白がれること探し放題ですって
Let's enjoy it! Searching for fun things as much as we want!
無限のフィールドね
It's an infinite field, isn't it?
パニングしなくてもいい ど真ん中直線
No need to pan, straight down the center!
つまりこれが僕の答えなんだ
In short, this is my answer!
胸を張れ 今を生きるその意味を 明くる日も明くる来る日も確かめて進め
Hold your head high, confirming the meaning of living now, day after day, and press on!
ワンダラー
Wanderer!!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
みんな、ありがとうございました！
Everyone, thank you so much!
えー、聴いていただいたのは、オリ曲メドレー…メドレーにしちゃいました、繋ぎましたよ！
Um, what you just listened to was an original song medley... I made it a medley and connected them!
そして、『世界で一番のアイドル』作詞をしました！この時ゃ「卒業」だなんてかけてなかったからね…本当に、あの、いっぱい聴いてほしい曲です。
And I wrote the lyrics for "Sekai de Ichiban no Idol"! Back then, I didn't write it thinking of "graduation"... It's a song I really want you to listen to a lot.
そして、『特者生存ワンダラダー!!』でした！
And that was "Tokusha Seizon Wander-la-der!!"!
はい、これを初めてね、出しましたね。
Yes, I performed this for the first time just now, didn't I?
えー、オリジナル楽曲ですけれど…
Um, it's an original song, but...
ちょっと語りたいこといっぱいあるんですけど…
There's a lot I want to talk about, but...
やっぱり、あの服…だよね？
It's got to be *that* outfit, right?
ってことでね、1秒着替えしてきました！
So, I did a 1-second costume change!
はい！やっぱりこれだよね、みんな！へい、こんかなたー！
Yes! It has to be this, right everyone? Hey, Kon-kanata~!
キャッチコピーは握力50kg、ギュギュッと握りつぶしちゃうぞ！ホロライブ4期生のかなたんこと天音かなたです！
My catchphrase is 50kg grip strength, I'll crush you tight! I'm Amane Kanata, also known as Kanatan from Hololive 4th Gen!
はい！ということでね、ロックバ…あぶないあぶない、危ない話は渡らないでおきまして…
Yes! So, rock ba... Whoops, whoops, let me not cross into dangerous territory...
このようなね、あの、感じでいきたいと思いますけれど…本当にオリジナル楽曲はね、フェスやイベント、ソロライブなど、他にもたくさんの思い出が詰まっていて…
I'd like to proceed like this, but really, original songs are packed with so many memories from festivals, events, solo live concerts, and more...
みんながたくさん聴いてくれたおかげと言いますか
Thanks to everyone listening to it so much,
本当にありがとうございます と思ってます
I am truly grateful, from the bottom of my heart.
えー、みんなね、あのー
Um, everyone...
この後ですね
after this,
22時10分から最後の「歌ってみた」
at 22:10, my final cover song...
みんなと約束してました
I promised everyone...
動画消えちゃって「歌い直そう」って言っていたね
since the video was deleted, I'd re-sing it,
「KING」を投稿するので、絶対見てくださいね！
I'll be posting "KING", so please watch it!
毎日一緒にいてくれた平民
To the Heimin who were with me every day,
ホロライブの大好きなメンバーたち
to my beloved Hololive members,
そしてたくさん支えてくださった、本当にお世話になった方々全ての方に感謝しています
and to everyone who supported me, I am deeply grateful to all of you.
夢のような時間は本当ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for this dreamlike time!
子供の頃のアイドルになりたいという夢が
My childhood dream of becoming an idol,
作詞作曲をしてみたいという夢も
and my dream of writing and composing music,
叶いました！
have both come true!
そして！
And...
最後の曲ですが、まだ歌うんですよ
for the last song, I still have one more to sing.
僕が初めて作詞作曲した楽曲があります
There's a song I wrote and composed for the first time.
今はいない同期・ココの卒業に合わせて
Written for the graduation of my late gen-mate, Coco,
4期生のトワ、ルーナ、わために捧げた楽曲です
dedicated to my 4th generation mates Towa, Luna, and Watame.
前を向いて笑顔でこの楽曲で活動を最後にしたいと思います
Looking forward with a smile, I want to end my activities with this song.
それでは聴いてください。「キセキ結び」
Please listen to: "Kiseki Musubi".
約束しようよ
Let's make a promise,
僕ら出会えたキセキ
so that the miracle of us meeting
忘れないように
will never be forgotten.
夢抱いて集う青春 アニメみたいな
Gathering with dreams, this youth is like an anime,
ハッピーなエンドになる かなたへ飛ぶよ
towards a happy ending, flying into the distance.
寝ぼけ眼 あくびして 今日は何をしようか？
Rubbing sleepy eyes and yawning, what shall we do today?
とわに続く海を駆ける
Running across the endless sea,
今は溜息より 勇気を
right now, more than sighs, give me courage.
諦めるなんてないの ここで歌う
Giving up isn't an option, I will sing right here.
僕の 声は聴こえてますか？
Can you hear my voice?
君に届け！
Reaching out to you!
学校の友達じゃきっとない出会いだった
A meeting we'd never have as school friends,
画面の先の遥か遠くまで
reaches far beyond the screen.
ささくれた言葉も 誰かの笑顔になる
Even harsh words turn into someone's smile.
それぞれの色で 星結ぶ軌跡
A trajectory connecting stars with our own colors,
キラキラ輝くステージに 連れて行くよ
I will take you to a stage shining bright.
泣いて笑ってはしゃいで 毎日ジェットコースター！
Crying, laughing, having fun—every day is a rollercoaster!
たまには寝転んでお昼寝しよう
Once in a while, let's lie down and take a nap.
ちょっと自信ないとき 小鳥とデュエットして
When I lack confidence, I duet with little birds.
今日だけは泣いちゃうこと許してね
Forgive me for crying just for today.
未来の僕がアルバム開く
The future me opens the album,
傷ついた写真だって宝物だ
even damaged photos are precious treasures.
僕の 愛が見えていますか？
Can you see my love?
君に届け！
Reaching out to you!
過去も個性も性格も違うけれど
Though our pasts, personalities, and traits differ,
弱気なときは目蓋ぎゅっとつむり
when feeling weak, I tightly close my eyes.
もう一回 もう一回 絶対に諦めない
One more time, one more time, I'll never give up.
前の背中追う下手っぴな僕でも
Even if I'm clumsy at chasing the back ahead,
君の隣に行きたくて 走るの
I run because I want to be by your side.
誰にも言えずに描いた夢が
The dream I drew without telling anyone,
たとえ叶わないとしても
even if it doesn't come true,
ボロボロの靴でも カッコよくなくても
even with worn-out shoes, even if I'm uncool...
幼いあの日の僕ならなんて言う？ 止まらないで
What would the young me say back then? "Don't stop."
初めて僕ら出会った日 まるで
The day we first met feels as though
昨日みたいに思い出すけど
it was just yesterday when I remember it, but...
もう行こうか 最後に今
Shall we go now? At last, right now,
重なる５人の奇跡
the miracle of the five of us overlapping.
僕の 声は聴こえてますか？
Can you hear my voice?
君に届け！
Reaching out to you!
黒板のメッセージ 桜のカーテンくぐって
The message on the blackboard, passing through the cherry blossom curtain,
僕らの声を聞いて ずっとずっと
listen to our voices, forever and ever.
嬉しい日
Happy days,
楽しい日
joyful days,
悲しい日 お別れの日も
sad days, and days of farewell too—
それぞれの色で 星結ぶ奇跡
A miracle tying stars together in each of our colors,
キラキラ輝くステージで
on this sparkling stage.
約束しよう
Let's make a promise.
いつかここで また会おう
Someday, right here, we'll meet again.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ホロライブ4期生 天音かなたでした！
I was Hololive 4th Generation, Amane Kanata!
6年間本当に幸せな日々でした！
These 6 years were truly such happy days!
へい民、不器用な僕を応援してくれてありがとう！
Heimin, thank you for supporting clumsy me!
ずっとずっと大好きだよ！
I love you forever and ever!
ずっとずっと宝物だよ！
You will always, always be my treasure!
みんな本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you all so very much!
ありがとう
Thank you...